You're never going to stop printing
money when I'm looking at constructing a
crypto portfolio to maximize my risk
adjusted returns. I generally look at
things most other cryptocurrencies end
up bleeding back to Bitcoin. Most also
one cycle will not be there in the
future.
What about XRP, Cardano?
Bitcoin would out for most altcoins.
It's hard to convince people when the
market is not very exciting and they
only want to join when the parabolic
phase of the cycle is occurred.
Where are we?
Bitcoin can sniff out where the money
supply is going to go before it goes
there. And when it recognizes that in
say half a year the money supply will
top out, that's when Bitcoin starts
going down. We're likely going to see a
pullback in the third quarter.
[Music]
We're at the Bitcoin Las Vegas
Conference, the biggest Bitcoin
conference in the world. I'm David Lynn.
I'm back with co-host
Bonnie Cheng
and we are with Ben Cowen of Into the
Cryptoverse. We're going deep into the
cryptoverse today with you, Ben.
That sounds great.
Deep into Bitcoin dominance, ETH going
home among other things
and we're we're going to be going home
afterward with a lot of knowledge about
Bitcoin. So, uh I think Bonnie has some
questions about your methodology first
before we're going to get your price
prediction for this cycle. There are
charts that you know me measure risk on
your platform, but Jack Mers from 21
Capital and uh Michael Sailor said risk
is not volatility is not risk, risk is
not volatility.
And what is your view?
Well, I think there's a big difference
between positive volatility and negative
volatility. uh there are certain things
like sharp ratios which I'm sure
everyone's heard of which punishes
positive volatility but other other
metrics like the sortino ratio does not
and so when I'm looking at constructing
a crypto portfolio uh to maximize my
risk adjusted returns I generally look
at things like the sortino ratio which
does not punish positive volatility
because at the end of the day you want
the price to go up right and you don't
really want to punish the asset for the
price going up
what do you mean punish
if you punish when I when say punish,
what I mean is if you're if you're
treating positive volatility as a
negative thing, then it might overall
want to reduce the allocation you have
of that asset in your portfolio. Um, but
I view positive volatility as a good
thing. And in fact, it's the positive
volatility that you know has brought us
all here.
Do you evaluate volatility as a metric
for how much of that particular asset
you should include in your portfolio? In
other words, if something has a higher
um higher standard deviation, not sharp
ratio, higher standard deviation
overall, do you allocate less of it or
more of it depending on your own risk
profile?
So, it it depends on what part of the
cycle or part of my journey you've asked
me that, right? When I was younger and
in jumping into the cryptoverse, I
definitely wanted more volatility.
Well, what is the guideline for people
to to know for themselves? I mean, like
it's like depending on your own age and
your own personality. I guess
it's a personal journey. It depends on
your age. It also depends on how much
you have, like you know, your your
overall net worth. Um, you know, when
you're young and you don't if you don't
have a lot, which was me a decade ago,
it made more sense to take on more risk
and and because the worst case scenario
was I I lose what little money I had,
right? But once you've been in the
crypto space for a long time, a lot of
people sort of veer more towards assets
like just Bitcoin um rather than getting
too um into other parts of the market
because they recognize that over the
longer period of time, Bitcoin is sort
of a a much more steady asset. It it
generally goes up over a long period of
time, whereas most other
cryptocurrencies end up bleeding back to
Bitcoin. Um, and so as I've gotten
older, I found myself preferring less
volatility over more volatility because
I really would prefer to just kind of
preserve what I have rather than chase,
you know, the next 100x gym that is is
being talked about at that part of the
cycle, if that makes sense.
Less volatility. Do you buy gold?
I do own gold. Um, I own more Bitcoin
than gold. M
historically, gold underperforms uh not
only Bitcoin but also risk assets like
the S&P. So over a long period of time,
uh precious metals don't really do that
well compared to risk assets. Uh but I I
do think there's still a place in a
portfolio for gold. Historically, in
prior cycles, I've always said about
like 3 to 5%, this cycle, I've said a
little bit more, like maybe seven to 8%,
but I don't really think it makes sense
to be, you know, too exposed to precious
metals because, I mean, they can go
decades without really doing much of
anything. And we actually just saw that
with gold, you know, from 2010 or so to
2023, 2024, price didn't really change.
And think about what Bitcoin
accomplished between 2010 and 2024. So,
you're the Bitcoin dominance guy. Yes.
Yes. Um, for regular investors, it's
just a number. How do you look at it?
So, I think Bitcoin dominance is I would
say the key to unlocking the secrets of
the cryptoverse. And the reason for that
is because a lot of people when they
think about their portfolio, they think
in terms of US dollars, right? If you
say, "What is your portfolio worth?" You
think in terms of all right, if I
denominated in US dollars, what's that
mean? And it makes sense because a lot
of people spend in terms of fiat
currencies. Um, but I think it makes a
lot more sense to denominate your
portfolio in Satoshi's because we
already know that fiat is going as to
zero over a long period of time. So it's
not really that big of a deal if an
asset goes up while the the under the
underlying currency is being devalued.
But if you're going to buy something
besides Bitcoin in the crypto market,
you're taking on more risk because I
think every other cryptocurrency is more
risky than Bitcoin. And so if you are
going to do it, you're going to want to
make sure you get a higher reward. The
problem for this cycle is that there
hasn't really been a great time to bet
on Bitcoin dominance going down, at
least not yet. And so the whole point is
that any individual altcoin can
outperform Bitcoin for some time, for a
few months, maybe a year, but a lot of
times the altcoins that were
outperforming Bitcoin in 2022 were
different than the ones in 2023 and
different than the ones in 2024 and now
probably the same thing in 2025. So for
most investors, including myself, it's
just a lot easier. I can sleep better at
night just keeping my portfolio mostly
Bitcoin uh rather than chasing altcoins.
Because if you look at altcoins on their
Satoshi valuation, they're a lot lower
this year than they were last year. And
they were lower last year than the year
before that. And so that is something
we've seen play out every cycle. The
only difference between this cycle is
that the dominance trend, the uptrend in
Bitcoin dominance has lasted far longer
because in prior cycles, in the last
cycle, it kind of ended in 2019 and then
it wicked above that in 2021. But
really, we have seen Bitcoin dominance
go up almost non-stop since mid to late
2020, mid to late 2021.
You said Bitcoin, sorry, fiat going as
to zero. Why?
Well, the purchasing power, the
purchasing power of because they're
never going to stop printing money,
right? They're never going to stop
printing money. Um, you know, if you
look at at what it costs to buy anything
today, it's so much more than it was 10
years ago, more than it was 50 years
ago, more than it was 100 years ago. In
fact, that's one of the reasons we're
incentivized to spend fiat currency is
because we know that because of
inflation, it's going to be worth less
tomorrow than it is today. And so,
because it's going to be worth less
tomorrow than it is today, it encourages
spending, right? Whereas with Bitcoin,
the idea is it'll be worth more tomorrow
than it is today. And so, it doesn't
really encourage you to want to spend
your Bitcoin if you think it's going to
be worth more later on than it is right
now.
Let me just play devil's advocate
because I think we're all Bitcoiners
here. So, someone's got to be the bad
guy. Listen, if I were to bet against
the future and I know that inflation is
going to erode purchasing power, I would
put a portion of my fiat away into some
low yielding product because I know with
certainty that I can at least match
inflation with like a 3 4% CD, whereas I
don't know for certain where Bitcoin is
going to go. So, I'm not going to put my
wealth and my savings on an uncertain
future whereas I can just hedge against
inflation and protect against purchasing
power depreciation. What would you how
would you respond to that?
No, I mean I think it's a really great
way to look at it. I think that a well
diversified portfolio is the way to go.
No one no one knows what the future
holds. Yeah.
Um when when I talk about sort of
allocations into Bitcoin and and Bitcoin
dominance, that's kind of in reference
to just my
crypto portfolio. Yeah.
Right. I'm not referencing,
you know, my portfolio in say low
expense ratio index funds or,
you know, I'm not generally thinking
like, oh, what's the Satoshi valuation
of this S&P 500 fund that I have? the
spy like I'm not thinking like that.
It's more so in the crypto markets. How
do I evaluate that? And I I think that
you know there is a time and a place for
for you know money market funds, CDs, T
bills, that kind of stuff. Um and and
that kind of goes back to the question
you were asking earlier. You know, where
do you go? Like how do you how do you
navigate that? Again, it depends on your
age. If you're younger, you have more
time to take riskier bets. And if it
doesn't work out in the short term,
well, hopefully you still have three or
four more decades for it to work out
before you retire. If you're in your
60s, you probably don't want to bet all
of that on one particular asset because
if something bad happens, you don't
necessarily have the time to wait for it
to come back. So, I think by having some
stuff like that and lower risk things,
it can at least help you sleep better at
night. And because we know Bitcoin is
volatile sometimes to the downside, we
just saw it drop to 70 74K, 73K,
something like that. By having something
where you're just earning the risk-free
rate, uh it gives you something to
potentially buy Bitcoin with. Um so I
think it's an excellent point and I
think that a well- diversified portfolio
needs to take that into account.
But my mom's retired friend said,
"Bonnie, you said Bitcoin is only going
up. Why can't I buy it with my
retirement money?
Well, over a long period of time, it's
probably true. But even with Bitcoin, if
you think about all prior cycles we've
had in 2022, it dropped what was it 77%.
In 2018, it dropped 84%. In 2014, it
dropped 87%. And and in 2011 20 Yes,
sometime around 2011, it dropped like
90%.
If you have the patience to watch it
play out over a very long period of
time, more likely more than likely will
go up over a long period of time. What a
lot of times happens is it's hard to
convince people
when the market is not very exciting and
then they only want to join when the
parabolic phase of the cycle is occur is
occurring.
Where are we?
So normally post having years are cycle
tops normally. uh 20 21 was 2017 was
2013 was so unfortunately all prior post
hopping years have been cycle tops. Uh
the good news is well well the bad news
is we have diminishing returns so we
should expect a lower return as measured
from low to high to high and low to low.
Uh but the good thing about diminishing
returns in this case is it also has
historically come with diminishing
losses. So even in the bare markets,
every subsequent bare market, Bitcoin
has dropped less and less and less. So,
you know, I think it's one of those
things where if you're going to hold it,
you have to be aware you're going to
have drops occasionally. And it usually
happens after, you know, euphoria phases
where and a lot of times when it happens
is when the other assets in the
cryptoverse start to do very very well
because when the froth rises, that's
when the market normally needs a
correction. If you even if you look at
it in a shorter time frame, in early
2025, uh, Bitcoin found a local top
around January 20th, uh, the same day
the new administration took office. And
and the reason is because, you know,
you're pricing in perfection. You're
pricing in a strategic Bitcoin reserve,
right? You're pricing in deregulation
and and all this stuff. And and then
when when things can't get any better in
the short term, you normally get a
correction, right? And so, I think there
was some elements of euphoria back then.
Uh, we cooled off going into into April.
Now we're getting a bounce into into the
spring and it makes sense because they
you know they had all the tariff tariff
tantrum to some degree and I I'm hoping
we'll see the current strength last a
little bit longer. I do think we will
see a pullback sometime in the third
quarter. Um third quarter historically
is pretty weak for Bitcoin. August and
September on average are the worst
months for Bitcoin. I'm pretty sure Q3
and 2022, 2023 and 2024 were all
slightly red for Bitcoin. So, probably
makes sense to be aware that there
likely will be a pullback in the third
quarter of the year,
but this is not the top.
I mean, hopefully not.
Bitcoin has changed the world. But what
if it could do more than just sit in
your wallet? Welcome to Core Dow, the
largest Bitcoin DeFi ecosystem.
Today's sponsor, Core, has over 1
million weekly users, $500 million in
total value locked, and more than 100
live projects. Core is the most advanced
platform for putting your Bitcoin to
work.
Core allows you to earn passive yield
with no principal risk. In partnership
with Maple Finance, Core is proud to
introduce LSTBTC,
liquid staked Bitcoin.
For the first time, Bitcoin holders can
earn sustainable passive yields without
giving up custody or taking up excessive
risk. LST BTC transforms Bitcoin into a
productive asset. By time locking your
BTC using proven onchain mechanics, you
unlock new staking rewards while
maintaining full transparency and
control. Stake Bitcoin and Core together
to earn even more thanks to a dynamic
dual staking system that rewards deeper
participation. This is more than DeFi.
It's the bridge between Wall Street and
Web 3. LST BTC is designed to power the
next generation of Bitcoin ETFs,
structured financial products, and
institutional-grade strategies.
Bitcoin finally working for you, not
financial advice. Visit cordow.org to
learn more.
You talk about ETH going home a lot.
What is ETH going home?
So, ETH did go home. So basically if you
if you look at even Bitcoin um you can
kind of look at look at the overall
price history and see that historically
it comes back down to sort of what you
might consider to be uh the fair value
which the fair value is kind of a
contentious topic anyways like what even
does that mean? If you look at Bitcoin
when it's sort of in the depths of bare
markets like the end of 2014, end of
2018, into 2022, and even the very
beginning of 2010, you can actually fit
that uh data to a logarithmic aggression
curve. And you can do the same thing
with Ethereum. So with Bitcoin, Bitcoin
went home, quote unquote home, back at
the end of 2022. So it went to the lower
regression band. It actually went
slightly below it. Went to around
$15,000. Ethereum never did, right? and
it it got close to going to its lower
regression band, but then it never did.
So, the idea was that at some point
during the cycle, Bitcoin will go down
when it normally goes up. And that just
happened, right? In January, February,
March, and April, we saw Bitcoin go down
when in normal post having years, it's
going up during that time. When that
happens each cycle, that's what normally
takes Ethereum down on its USD pair and
on its Bitcoin pair. And that's what we
just saw happen. So, we just saw
Ethereum quote unquote go home. In this
case, home is like $1,500 to $1,600. Um,
it's since bounced up. I'm not yet 100%
convinced it's going to outperform
Bitcoin at this point. I I still think
there's a decent chance you'll see
Bitcoin dominance continue to go up for
a while. Um, primarily because of the
altcoin market. I think the altcoin
market kind of still needs to go home
itself. I think Ethereum has Ethereum
has I think the rest of the altcoin
market is still overvalued against
Bitcoin. In fact, if you look at the
collective altcoin market and divide and
you subtract out stable coins and then
if you do that and then you divide it by
the Bitcoin market cap every cycle there
tends to be a low and that cycle is
around 0.25. Meaning historically,
altcoins bottom whenever they're
collectively equivalent to approximately
25% of Bitcoin's market cap. At the time
of this recording, altcoins are at 35%
of Bitcoin's market cap. So, a lot of
people keep hoping for alt season, but
the alt season in 2021 occurred from an
altcoin valuation against Bitcoin below
25%. And in 2017, it occurred at a
valuation of 25%. So, I continue to
think that Bitcoin will suck that
liquidity out of the altcoin market
until they're at least at 25% of
Bitcoin's market cap. In 2017, they hit
25% of Bitcoin's market cap at the very
end of October, early November. So, if
history repeats itself, we could see
altcoins bleed back to Bitcoin uh for a
few more months, potentially up until
November. Even in that case, even if
they do get a nice bounce in November,
um it, you know, those phases of the
cycle only last for a couple months,
right? And then you spend another almost
four years watching Bitcoin dominance go
up again. So I I think Bitcoin dominance
if you can understand it and you know if
you think about it a lot uh you know on
the surface level it seems like well
how's this helpful like you can't go buy
Bitcoin dominance right it's not
something you can just say like oh I
bought 10 units of Bitcoin dominance but
if you understand that opportunity costs
every dollar into an altcoin is a dollar
not into Bitcoin and you just don't want
to watch you you don't want to watch an
altcoin go up 10% that you bought while
Bitcoin went up 100% right that's not
really a win. It's like you took on more
risk and got less of a return.
So that begs the question as to what we
do with the information you provided. So
if you assume that Bitcoin dominance
will go up, can you use that as an ass
allocation tool? Meaning let's say
currently it's about 64%. Let's say
it'll retrace at 70% uh 2021 high, do
you then allocate more of your portfolio
to Bitcoin knowing that you believe
Bitcoin dominance will go up? And vice
versa, if you think alts will suck up
more of Bitcoin's liquidity and it'll go
down, do you allocate more to alts?
Yeah. So, for most of the cycle, I've
been about 99% Bitcoin because I just
assumed that it would Bitcoin would
outperform most altcoins. There are
times in the cycle where it felt like I
was wrong. Absolutely. We we've seen
plenty of altcoins. I mean, we even saw
Ethereum do really well against Bitcoin
in mid22 going into the merge. We saw
Salana do really well against Bitcoin in
2023 uh with all the memecoin hype. Uh
at every point in the cycle, there are
some altcoins that are doing better than
Bitcoin. And a lot of people will see
that and they'll cherrypick a few
altcoins and say, "Well, Bitcoin
dominance is not useful." The problem is
that stuff's only obvious in hindsight,
right? You cannot know what altcoin is
going to derly out form Bitcoin any
given year. And so, if you kind of
accept that and you just say, "Well, I
assume that Bitcoin dominance is going
to go higher because all Bitcoin pairs
are not are still well off the range
lows and I know that last cycle altcoins
didn't even bottom against Bitcoin until
quantitative tightening ended, which
still hasn't even happened this cycle."
M um and if you look at ratios between
like the Fed funds rate and the terminal
rate in order to match what happened
last cycle before altcoins bottom
against Bitcoin, we'd still need another
65 basis points of rate cuts. So I think
absolutely if you are confident we are
in a Bitcoin dominance uptrend whenever
the Fed signals that monetary policy is
going to tighten right whenever that
signal comes if you just go into that
the next few years and you say I'm going
to assume that most altcoins will bleed
to Bitcoin. There's going to be a time
where it's going to be tempting to go
into the altcoin market. they're going
to collect lead. I think it makes sense
to just stick with Bitcoin during that
during those few years. And yeah, like
there's going to be times during the
year where it's it's going to make sense
to think like, oh, maybe I should put
something towards out, but over the over
the long haul, alts are oscillators at
best against Bitcoin and 99.999% of them
are just bleeding against Bitcoin over
the macro scale anyways.
So, yeah, I I think that if if altcoins
were at the range lows, uh then, you
know, you you could argue it would be
worth the risk a little bit more. But
even at all times in the cycle, no
matter what, I think it makes sense to
have a majority of your crypto portfolio
in Bitcoin because the altcoins are just
a lot more speculative. Um, they come
and go. That's the problem with
altcoins.
Is it dubiously speculative?
It is. It is. And in fact, I mean, a lot
of, you know, a lot of the asset class
rate is dubious speculation. It's the
promise of of what altcoins will provide
in the future, but a lot of them, you
know, are are false promises. They don't
actually pan out. Um, so I do I do think
that Bitcoin is kind of the the the main
asset to to stay in for the for the
macro scale and and just to look at um
if you go to any of the the main
websites, you know, Coin Market Cap or
anything like that and you look at their
historical tools and and you look at the
top 10 in 2013 and the top 10 in 2014,
you know, you won't find many coins that
were around the top 10 for more than
more than one cycle, more than a couple
cycles. There's a few exceptions to the
rule. You have like Ethereum, you have a
couple others, but most alts that are in
the top 10 one cycle will not be there
in the future.
What about XRP? Um, Cardano this cycle.
They seem to come back a little bit.
Yeah, but even even ADA ADA is is now at
700 SATs and at its high it was, you
know, 4,000 SATs or something, right?
XRP and if you look at something like a
metric like XRP dominance in 2017 I I I
don't have a chart in front of me but in
2017 I I believe XRP dominance was like
20 to 30%. As crazy as that sounds today
it's like 1 to 2%. Right. So yeah it it
seems like the altcoins can come back
but then you kind of look back at it you
know XRP I don't even know if it even
has taken out its 2018 all-time high. If
it has, it only barely did it. So, I
mean, if you think about that, if
Bitcoin were at the same valuation XRP
were at with reference to its, you know,
two cycles ago all-time high, that would
put Bitcoin at around $19,000. So, it it
can be easy to cherrypick lows for
altcoins and say they've kind of come
back. But the reality is is had you
bought XRP in 2018, you're actually
down. Yeah.
You know, whereas at any point if you
bought Bitcoin in 2018, you're up.
Um, can I say that we're not going to
see the altcoin season like 2021 where
everything went up?
There's a possibility of that in so in
2017 we had alt season when all Bitcoin
pairs hit the range lows. But last cycle
when all Bitcoin pairs hit 25% of
Bitcoin's market cap, it actually
occurred on the preh havinging year and
it did not correspond with alt season.
Alt season was still a year and a half
away. So I I think altcoins going down
on their Bitcoin pairs to 0.25, 25. It's
a sufficient condition or it's a it's a
necessary condition for a quote unquote
alt season, but it's not sufficient,
right? Like you need more than that. You
need retail to return. This cycle, we
actually haven't really seen as much
interest in retail investors as we have
in prior cycles. And when you have that,
when you have social interest so low,
there's only one Bitcoin.
Tell me why. Because people can see, oh,
Bitcoin is performing very well against
every other asset. Why aren't they here?
because a lot of people chase altcoins
and
they and and we have a lot of metrics
that we look at on our website as well
where a lot of interest occurs whenever
altcoins start rallying. So in November
of 2024, in November of 2023, we saw
altcoins temporarily surging against
Bitcoin. That's when we had a return of
retail investors. A lot of social
interest uh metrics were going back up.
But anytime Bitcoin moves without the
altcoin market, kind of like now, right?
and we haven't really seen a ton of
movement in the altcoin market. Uh you
just don't really see as as much
interest because also Bitcoin's being
driven as well a lot by institution
institutional demand right now. Uh
whereas that hasn't we haven't really
seen the same extent with altcoins. Um I
I think one thing about this market
cycle it's teaching good investing
principles to a lot of people right like
just kind of slow and steady often wins
the race rather than chasing the next
100x gym because someone said all
season's around the corner. there's
absolutely a chance you don't get one. I
I think if you don't get one this year,
it it it would only be due to um the
macro environment, you know,
deteriorating in a way that doesn't
allow for sort of the the riskiest
assets at the end of the risk curve to
kind of get that final whip back up to
the upside.
Have you seen the chart where M2 money
supply went up? Well, is going up?
Yes. Yes.
If that is the case, isn't alt season
coming? Well, money supply has been
going up for years and there's plenty of
times in prior cycles where the money
supply goes up and you still didn't get
an all season. Um, we also have to
remember that the chart you're referring
to, the M2 money supply, it's also a
function of the dollar because uh the
DXY, the Dixie, uh, if you denominate
all those local currencies into US
dollars, you know, the strength of the
dollar plays a big role. So, one of the
reasons that the money spy is going up a
lot right now is because the dollar has
collapsed. Um, and also, you know,
correlation with money supply and risk
assets over a long enough period of
time. They're both going to go up and to
the right, right? They're never going to
stop printing money. Risk assets are
never going to stop going higher over a
longer period of time. But there are
times when those correlations break
down. For instance, uh, in Q3 of 2023 or
in Q4 of 2023, I believe, uh, the money
supply went down, but crypto went up.
So, there are times when those metrics
actually diverge. And even even in in
all things, I mean, we we saw the dollar
and the 10-year yield highly correlated
for for a long time, but then now
they've kind of decoupled and and we see
the 10ear yield going up while the
dollar has collapsed. So, a lot of times
you'll see correlations play out. Um,
it's trying to figure out when those
correlations stop being useful is is the
hard part.
What what is the relationship just off
dubtailing off of Bonnie's question,
what is the relationship between M2
money supply and and the crypto space
overall? Uh, M2 is growing at currently
4.4%. up a little bit in terms of annual
percent change.
Um, so let's tie that in.
Yeah. I mean, the idea is is if you look
at I mean, if you look at the S&P 500
divided by the money supply, we're at
same valuations today as we were in
1998, right? So, if you relate that to
crypto, the argument for some assets is
that they're not going up. And I'm not
saying this about Bitcoin, but like just
a lot of altcoins in general. They're
not necessarily going up because they're
fundamentally valuable. They're just
going up because the amount of money we
have, you know, just in society is going
up. And people want to seek out yield.
More people, some people will take on
risk. Some people will take on less
risk. And risk assets will generally go
higher in that case. So over a long
enough period of time, risk assets
generally trend up and to the right
because the money supply is going up and
to the right. But there are times
throughout history where they don't
always correlate. For instance, if you
look at 2008 and 2000, I don't really
think the money supply went down much at
all during those periods, but you still
had large downturns. And I could be
wrong, but I I think you you still had
fairly large downturns in risk assets
even without as massive a drops in in
the money supply. So, yeah, like it's a
good correlation. And I think during
bull markets, it appears like they're
tracking each other because they're both
going up and to the right. Um, but if
you look at M2 and look at Bitcoin,
historically, Bitcoin tops out around I
want to say about half a year before the
money supply does, right? So, in if you
had waited for M2 to top out
convincingly in 2022 to, you know, to if
you wanted to derisk and get out of
Bitcoin, you would have ended up selling
Bitcoin at the bottom because it
basically was at the bottom when M2
topped out. Um, same thing the cycle
before in 2018. if you waited for M2 to
start going down, Bitcoin was already at
$6,000 at that point. It did get another
50% drop after that. So, I think there's
a lot of people following it, but I and
this is kind of a contentious view and I
I kind of expressed this on Twitter a
few weeks ago and it was not really
wellreceived, but I'll just kind of
reiterate it and I think there is
there's a lot of people I think that are
assuming that that Bitcoin goes up.
Like, if the money spike goes up, then
if we can see the money spike going up,
then the assumption is that Bitcoin will
go up. But I I kind of take the other
side of that. I I think that I like
Bitcoin as an asset. I think it's a
really good asset. I think that Bitcoin
can sniff out where the money supply is
going to go before it goes there. And
when it recognizes that in say half a
year the money supply will top out,
that's when Bitcoin starts going down.
So I would argue, and again it's a
contentious view, I would almost argue
that Bitcoin is leading the money supply
and not lagging it.
So we are at a top. That's not
necessarily true. I mean, it it it just
means that if you wait for the money
supply to go down,
then you've waited too long, right?
So, like the point is is like people
want an indicator to tell them when to
sell. But unfortunately, there's not
going to be a single indicator that's
going to to time the exact top, right?
So, there's a lot of uncertainty. If
everyone knew if everyone had one
indicator that could time the exact top,
like that just doesn't make sense that
that would how accurate that would even
be. I think the point is is that
whenever you start to see Bitcoin go
down, it's more of a signal that the
money supply will eventually follow.
Money supply going up in my opinion is
not indicative of Bitcoin going up. I
think Bitcoin leads it's like the stock
market. Do you wait for look at all
prior recessions with stock market if
you wait for the recession to be
declared the bottom occurred two weeks
ago, right? So it's the same thing with
Bitcoin, right? you wait if you wait for
um you know if if if you wait for the
money spy to top out it's it's already
it's too late that doesn't mean that the
top is in right it just means that it's
not necessarily the best indicator to
tell you when the top's in because if
you overlay M2 and Bitcoin Bitcoin
always tops out about half a year before
the money supply dies. So let's get your
prediction then top and bottom or range
for the rest of the year. Q you
mentioned Q uh Q3 may be tough
especially for uh the fall season.
Yeah. Yeah. So, kind of going into this
year, I I thought January 20th would
mark a high, at least a local high. And
my view was basically that if 2024 held,
if the if the high from 2024 held as
support in the pullback, then Bitcoin
could go to all-time highs again. And we
held at like 70, we we went to like 74K,
the high from 2024 was like 73.8. So, we
have gone to new alltime highs. We have
not seen total market cap follow that
though yet. Total market cap is still at
a lower high. So, we are seeing some
divergences there. We really would like
to see confirmation of that. I think
that we're likely going to see a
pullback in the third quarter. We also
saw a similar pattern in 2023 and in
2024 and in 2022. It just seems to be a
common thing. Obviously, like I could be
wrong, right? Like there's always a
chance we just go up into Q3, but one of
the reasons I think there'll be a
pullback is if you look at some of the
macro data, initial claims tend to go up
around the summertime. They went up in
the last couple of years. So, I I think
you'll probably see initial claims start
to tick a little bit higher. that could,
you know, that could put some
uncertainty. Um, I don't really think
initial claims are an issue until
they're printing 300K. I I think that is
is kind of where it becomes more
problematic, but we haven't seen that.
Why Why are we looking at initial
claims? Are you trying to use that as a
gauge for Fed activity?
Yeah. I I I think that the Fed will
likely because if going back to Bitcoin
dominance, which is thing, you know, I
if if you're trying to figure out like
when Bitcoin dominance is going to top
out, you need a reason for the Fed to
become less hawkish, right? need the Fed
to uh loosen monetary policy. If if
initial claims start to go up in Q3 and
and it, you know, it leads to some more
macro uncertainty, maybe we get a rate
cut, right? Right now, the next
projected rate cut is not till
September. They've talked about ending
quantitative tightening.
Waller said potentially se Jul July if
tariffs go down to 10% across the board.
Yeah. So, the problem right now, and I I
think this is where the the Fed is in a
tough position and why I think there's
going to be uh some weakness in the
third quarter. I I think the problem
right now is that you're going to see
some of them some of the labor market
data just show some weakness in the
summer like it normally does, right?
Like it normally does. And I I think
that you're going to couple that with at
least a temporary bump up in inflation.
I'm not saying that it's going to be a
I've always been in the disinflationary
camp, you know, for for years I've been
in the disinflationary camp. I think
that a repeat of the 1970s is is
unlikely where you have three waves, but
that doesn't mean you can't get a couple
of kind of scary data points induced by
some of these tariffs, right? Because at
the end of the day, there will likely be
some of that stuff passed on to
consumers whether we like it or not. And
I think that could it's possible that we
would have gotten a cut in July, but
maybe we don't think about it. We just
had negative GDP in Q1. Yeah. Right.
If you if you had if someone had said
we're going to have negative GDP in Q1,
you probably would have assumed we'd get
a rate cut, right? I mean, it would make
sense, right? If we had negative GDP, we
get a rate cut. I think one of the
reasons that we keep not getting rate
cuts is because inflation expectations
are going through the roof right now.
Inflation expectations right now, I
believe, are as high as they've been
since 1981.
Or POW just doesn't like Trump.
I mean, look, anything's possible.
Anything's possible, but but look, look
at the long end of the yield curve. The
long end of the yield curve is also
going up. And I mean it kind of goes to
show you that if you really want the
long end to go down, you have to have
lower lower asset prices.
Bitcoin leading the markets, which is a
contentious view by your point. But if
you think that Bitcoin leads M2 and the
monitor's view is that M2 leads
inflation, does Bitcoin by the transit
of property lead inflation?
I think well I think there
I think there is some validity to that.
um M2 going up is certainly going to
cause a lot of inflation, right? I think
I don't think that's like a contentious
view.
I I do think that if you think about I
if you think about like logically what
happened in 2021, what happened? Risk
assets everywhere went parabolic. And
then as that happened, we had the wealth
effect, right? The wealth effect. If
people feel wealthy, they feel richer,
they're more likely to spend there.
There's going to be higher demand, which
and then and and you look at when the
inflationary peak happened last cycle
happened in 2022. What happened in a
bare market? You know, that's when the
that's when we hit 9% inflation. I think
it happened in sort of the first half of
2021. We had core inflation peak out in
the second half of 2021. I think there's
solidity to that, but I think it's
mostly related to the wealth effect.
People just feeling richer. If you feel
richer, you're more likely to go spend
money. If you're more likely to spend,
it's going to lead to to higher prices
because you're going to have higher
demand. I want to close with this
because earlier you said um we don't
know when to buy or sell but if we just
uh sign up for your platform we will
know
right
did I say that um uh so I basically what
I do with Bitcoin is I just I buy it
whenever it's below a certain risk level
right so like in prior cycles I bought
it when it was below what I consider to
be sort of like the 0.5 risk level kind
of like anything below that this cycle
I've gotten a little bit more
conservative um but I think as long as
you have a plan like you're you're
probably going to look back in 30 years
and be like, "Okay, that worked." Right?
If you're going to come in and buy
Bitcoin at like a 0.9 risk level like it
was in 2021 in, you know, like in early
2021 or in 2017 or in 2013, you just
have to know you're going to be holding
it back for a while, right? Because once
you've once the risk level is that high
for that cycle, you've convinced
everyone you're going to convince that
cycle, right? There's going to be a
downturn in the market. This cycle, we
haven't really seen Bitcoin risk go that
high. it actually still continues to be
more like 2019 than anything else where
the Bitcoin risk level just kind of goes
up to like 06.7 risk in these in these
rallies, but it doesn't go all the way
up and and I think I I think that's
probably going to continue for a while,
which is a good thing. I mean, the
minute it goes to a really high risk
level, that's when you really have to
start preparing for a larger downturn.
Um, so until that time though, I mean,
until that time, you could argue that,
you know, the whole alt season stuff
doesn't even usually happen until after
Bitcoin has seen that stuff. So, it's
seen those parabolic rise to the higher
risk band. So, if Bitcoin does go up
there, then maybe you get an allseason.
And if Bitcoin doesn't, you're still
better off with Bitcoin than alt.
All right. Well, follow Ben Cowan and
into the cryptoverse down below. Thank
you, Ben.
Thank you. Thanks D.